

Leandro E. Colombo Viña

Professor // Developer



9 Octubre 1981



Larrea 910 8°D, CABA



+54 9 11 3001-5328



http://leo.bitson.com.ar



colomboleandro@bitson.com.ar

About me ——

Over the last 13 years I've been working on Education and since 2013 I've founded BITSON, with other IT professionals, our own democratic & cooperative enterprise. In BITSON we develop free software and hardware, mainly with access control turnstiles and web applications. I've gained experience in every field related to web applications development.

Frontend Backend DevOps Linux REST APIs

Entrepreneurship*3 Teaching*4 Time Management*4 Analyst*5

Python

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

[Interests]

I'm a FLOSS enthusiast. I've been using Free and Open Source Software since 2009. Promoting, attending, participating and organizing events related to FLOSS. I work using the industry best practices like standard coding styles, git-flow, SCRUM, TDD and many others.

Education

	in progress	
2014-2015	Computer Science Teacher	INSPT-UTN
2011-2014	Applied Informatics Grade point average: 9.29. National flag bearer 2013	INSPT-UTN
2008-2008	Instructor	CFP 34
1995-2000	Electronics Technician	Pío IX (A-66)

UNLa

Courses & Certifications

since 2017 Digital Technologies for Education

2016	Scrum Grand Master. SCEU-FRBA-UTN
2015	Digital & Social Media Operator. FUNDESCO, Ministry of Labor
2015	Remotee worker. FUNDESCO, Ministry of Labor
2014	Linux Certified Security System. Carrera Linux Argentina
2013	C Expert. Carrera Linux Argentina
2012	Project Management Executive Program. SCEU-FRBA-UTN
2011	Linux System Administrator Expert. Carrera Linux Argentina
2008	Multimedia products creation. CFP 34

Experience

2014-hoy	Business Development Manager, Founding Par Project Manager. Software & Hardware deve Trainning.http://www.bitson.com.ar/	
2010-hoy	Associate Professor Teaching 5 courses in the career of Systems the academic council.	IFTS18 Analysis & Member of
2011-2014	Consultant Networking. GNU/Linux System administrationing.	freelance on. Professional Train-
2007-2015	Instructor Python, Networking & GNU/Linux Basics. Eduteachers 2.0. Informatics 101.	CFP34 ucational Resources for
2010-2014	Community Manager Google Apps for Educations administrator & s	CFP34 social media.
2004-2014	SysAdmin / Teacher	Pío IX
2000-2004	Laboratory technician	Celtronics SRL/IMD SRL

Other information

2016	Organizer Python Conference Argentina, Bahía Blanca.		
2015	Founding Partner & Treasurer Python Argentina NGO.		
2014-2015	Speaker at FLISOL http://bitson.com.ar/flisol/git		
2014	Salesian Cooperators Center Manager.		
2010-2012	Conference on Educational Technologies		
2011	Course Continuing Education Professional Technical Education -		
2008	DGEGP Digital Reflex Photography, Digital edition.		